# Alex Inga

# Front-End Engineer

Philadelphia, PA (484)-620-4903 https://www.alexinga.com/ alexinga98@gmail.com

### **ABOUT ME**

A result driven Front-End Engineer with 3+ years of experience, specializing in HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, WordPress, and PHP. I'm experienced in building websites or web applications using responsive web design to enhance front-end design while improving the user experience.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS 3
- JAVASCRIPT(ES6)
- React.js
- Redux
- Bootstrap
- Typescript
- Sass
- Jest
- RESTFUL API
- Backend API
- PHP
- GIT
- WordPress
- CMS Development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Aragon Company** - Front-End Developer

April 2024 - October 2024

 Develop and maintain websites and landing pages for affiliate marketing partners, leveraging HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP to ensure responsive and engaging user experiences.

- Design and implement user-friendly, modular components in React.js for an in-house web application, enhancing functionality and user interaction.
- Create reusable and customizable style components for both web applications and WordPress CMS, streamlining design consistency across platforms.
- Integrate APIs seamlessly into web applications using React.js, improving data flow and user engagement.
- Refactor and optimize PHP codebases, focusing on scalability, reusability, and improved maintainability.

# **Consumer Focus Marketing** - Front-End Developer

Jan 2024 - April 2024

- Translate user requirements from adobe xd into scalable websites. Optimizing websites with WordPress management system, and maintaining databases from Mysgl.
- Using bootstrap, html, javascript to create web pages, and coordinate with cross-functional teams to identify opportunities to enhance web page responsiveness.

# **beMarketing** - Front-End Developer

Apr 2022 - July 2023

- Design user interfaces and websites for a digital agency delivering web development services for clients using html, css, javascript, and php.
- Translate user requirements into scalable code, develop prototypes, conduct wireframing activities using figma, and ensure alignment with client business specifications.
- Perform testing on web pages with Jest, analyze user feedback, and coordinate with cross-functional teams to identify opportunities to enhance web page responsiveness.

#### **UpWork** - Front-End Developer

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022

- Design, develop, and code web applications for customer accounts, which includes debugging issues, diagnosing root causes, and identifying solutions.
- Create responsive designs for mobile applications, built wireframe, and developed prototypes for web development projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

Delaware County Community College, 901 Media Line Rd, Media, PA -

Aug 2016 - June 2020

GPA 3.2.

# **REFERENCE**

- Evolet Davidoff Software Engineer, 484-745-7805 davidoffevolet@gmail.com
- Phil Squarcetta Software Engineer, 610-996-0053
- Kevin Skilton Software Engineer, 610-324-5641